helpfreely.org 2019-07-13

# Helpfreely - Privacy Policy

PRIVACY POLICY

Service provided by the HELP FREELY FOUNDATION, F.C., hereinafter ("H.F.F."), domiciled in Calle Eduardo Benot, Number 1, 6th Floor, Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, 35007, Spain. H.F.F. is a nonprofit corporation organized and existing under the laws of SPAIN and duly registered at the Spanish "Registro Autonómico de Fundaciones" with the Charity Number: ES G-76201334.

OVERVIEW

Helpfreely.org faciliates fundraising that benefits nonprofits, associations, and any other eligible organizations (“Cause”), made possible by the online purchases of products or services that supporters of these Causes complete while shopping at participating merchant partners (“Partner”). Helpfreely.org is fully owned by the H.F.F., and references made to “we” or “our” or “us” in this privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") or mentions of Helpfreely.org refer to both Helpfreely.org and the H.F.F.

The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to explain how data is collected, used, and shared with respect to our Services (the " **Services** "), the Helpfreely.org website (the “ **Site** ”), and our Helpfreely Application (“HelpfreelyApp™”). Users and Causes may use our Services, including the HelpfreelyApp™, at no cost to them. If you would like additional information, you can view our Terms of Service at www.helpfreely.org/es/terms-and-conditions/ and our FAQs at www.helpfreely.org/faq. Your use of any of the Helpfreely.org Services means that you allow us to use, collect, and share information that you provide as explained below in this Privacy Policy.

**Free Access and Use of Our Website**

Helpfreely.org offers its users free and open access to the Site. However, some of the services and content made available by the H.F.F. or third parties via our Site may require that a User first register for the service or product and then pay a specific fee as outlined in the corresponding Special Conditions, which will be made readily available in any such case.

**Personal Data Provided by Users at Registration**

Following the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), if you are a Registered User, we inform you that the personal data provided, whether yours or of a third party whose consent is legitimately collected, and any other personal data provided throughout the relationship will be included in a database owned by the H.F.F. in order to facilitate:

  * Access to a private User admin (“Admin”);
  * Becoming a supporter of the H.F.F ("Heroes");
  * Setting and saving personal preferences, such as selecting up to three Causes to support with your online purchases. These settings can be saved so that you can access them even if you clear your browser cookies or access the Services from a different computer;
  * Tracking your transactions;
  * Participate in surveys to raise extra funds, and, in order to participate, we may require that you provide certain demographic and/or personally identifiable information. These kinds of surveys are always optional, and your participation is always provided on a voluntary basis. During registration, there is also the option of providing demographic information (such as geographic location, gender, or age). You may choose to make this information available to us at your discretion.
  * Support ticket services;
  * Use of our referral links to raise extra funds for your main cause;
  * Applying to become a Legend of Helpfreely.org ("Legend");
  * Receiving news by email regarding changes to the Services, as well as additional Services, deals, special events, programs, or discounts to be offered to Helpfreely.org Users. To stop receiving these emails at any time, please opt out by modifying your account settings or by clicking on the unsubscribe link at the bottom of the email.

The acceptance of this clause constitutes consent to receive communications via postal mail, email, or equivalent means, such as SMS to your mobile phone.

Your personally identifiable information is used for the purposes described above, as well as to manage your account and personal settings, track the funds you raise, send you communications by email, reply to your questions or requests for information, and, in general, to provide you with our Services. In the case of a purpose that we have not specifically identified herein these terms, your personally identifiable information will be used for the purpose stated when you provide it.

We guarantee a responsible use and confidentiality of personal data, and you may exercise your rights of access, rectification, cancellation, and opposition by notice to the address of the H.F.F. or by sending an email to management@helpfreelyfoundation.org with the reference "Protection Data" accompanied by a copy of Your id card or passport.

Personally identifiable data via our Site or Services is never collected unless you provide it, such as during registration at the Site (which is not required) or in the case that you choose to contact us and give us your personal data, such as your email address.

**Third Parties**

This Privacy Policy concerns only the information that Helpfreely.org collects.

Some Helpfreely.org Partners, such as advertisers and marketing agencies, affiliate networks, analytics services, and other agents, may also use different kinds of cookies, pixel tags, and related technologies via our Services.

It is important to note that the H.F.F., as the entity in charge of the database, will at all times remain responsible for the use of the information that you voluntarily provide while you are part of our network. However, this does not mean that we will not be held responsible for any data management carried out by our Partners, who are required to comply to any applicable laws at all times.

Any information that our business Partners may collect via these kinds of tracking technologies will remain anonymous and will not be connected to your personally identifiable information. The purpose of collecting such data may include targeting advertisements, determining site usage, analysis of advertising results or other activities, as well as other purposes. Helpfreely.org business associates include but are not limited to Ebay, Yahoo, Amazon, Google, AffiliRed, Linkshare Rakuten, Adtraction, MGM Resorts International, Commission Junction, ShareASale, Admitad, Affiliate Window, Affilinet, Belboon, Effinity, Euroads, Impact Radius, 1mpact Revolution, Public-Idées, TradeTracker, Webgains, Zanox, and Tradedoubler. If you would like to understand better how these companies use this data, please read the privacy policy provided by each company.

You are no longer at our Site when you visit the page of one of the Causes or Shops or access any external website via a link from our Site, and these third party entities may employ cookies and other tracking technologies on their own sites, which may, among other purposes, identify you as a Helpfreely.org User and serve the purpose of helping these third parties identify purchases. A third-party “affiliate network” may be used to do this on the behalf of many merchants. Any personal data or other information that these third parties collect while you use their websites or that you voluntarily make available to them falls under the terms of each third party’s respective privacy policy.

Within our Services, you will find links to other websites that Helpfreely.org neither owns nor controls. We will not be held responsible for any content of these websites, nor for their individual privacy practices.

**Use of Our Site by Children**

Helpfreely.org believes it is important to protect the privacy of children. If you are a parent or guardian and believe that Helpfreely.org has collected personally-identifiable information linked to a minor under the age of 12, we ask that you let us know by contacting us using the information listed below. Helpfreely.org promises to make every reasonable effort to eliminate any such information from our records.

**Storage**

Your information may be stored on our Site for the purposes outlined in this privacy policy and during the necessary time period, which may be indefinite. Any such information is currently stored in a cloud server infrastructure (content delivery network technology) provided by OVH Hosting in Canada.

**Geolocalization**

To ensure the correct functioning of the Services, the User approves and authorizes Helpfreely for the collection of data related to the localization, tracking, or geolocalization of his or her computer, mobile device, or or any other electronic device of a similar nature.

**Security**

Helpfreely.org is very concerned about keeping you and your personal information secure while using our Services. We adhere to generally accepted industry standards to ensure the protection of personal information that is submitted to us, both during its transmission and after receiving it. However, Helpfreely.org will use commercially responsible methods to ensure the security of your personal information and shall, at all times, adhere to the legislation set forth by the Personal Data Protection Act (15/99) and Royal Decree (1720/2007). If you would like to know more about what we do to keep our Users secure while visiting our Site, please get in touch with us via our contact form.

**Changes to the Privacy Policy**

Helpfreely.org retains the right to make changes to this Privacy Policy whenever necessary. Any modifications that we make will be posted on our Site, so we advise our Users to stay up-to-date by reviewing the Privacy Policy from time to time. You may also be notified of changes to our terms by email (provided you have registered to receive email communications from us) or via a notice on our Site.

**Duration and Termination of Services**

The Services and the content of the Site will be made available for an indefinite period of time, except in the case of exceptional circumstances that make this impossible due to force majeure or technological errors. However, the H.F.F. reserves the right to terminate or suspend any Services or content available for free via the Site at any time and according to our own discretion. 

**Governing law**

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by and construed in accordance with the laws of Spain, without regard to its conflict-of-laws rules or provisions. You give consent to the personal and exclusive jurisdiction and courts sitting located in Las Palmas de G.C. (SPAIN) to resolve any legal matter arising from this Privacy Policy.
